<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>noexec.net</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on noexec.net</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 22:06:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenBSD 7.7 released</title>
      <link>/posts/2025/20250429-openbsd-7.7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 22:06:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2025/20250429-openbsd-7.7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exciting times! OpenBSD 7.7 has been released, time to upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was actually released a couple of days ago, but to be honest&#xA;I felt the process was a little scary. Not to spoil anything but&#xA;it was quite uneventful. I also wanted to wait a little to see&#xA;some other reports on the upgrade process, and they seemed to be&#xA;all positive.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-upgrade&#34;&gt;The upgrade&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I made sure everything was up to date first by running &lt;code&gt;syspatch&lt;/code&gt;&#xA;and &lt;code&gt;pkg_add -Uu&lt;/code&gt;, and then finally the big &lt;code&gt;sysupgrade&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Initial OpenBSD setup and configuration</title>
      <link>/posts/2025/20250425-openbsd-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Apr 2025 19:10:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2025/20250425-openbsd-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Having just ordered an OpenBSD VPS which is now online and exposed to the world,&#xA;I want to lock it down a little by changing the SSH config as well as the firewall&#xA;rules.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ssh&#34;&gt;SSH&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I like to start by disabling direct root-login, as well as disabling password&#xA;logins. The reason being that there are bots constantly scanning every IPv4&#xA;address on the internet, looking for known vulnerabilities I guess, as well as&#xA;some bots trying to log in through SSH. By disabling password-logins&#xA;you efficiently stop their brute-force attempts on passwords, and if you have &lt;code&gt;doas&lt;/code&gt;&#xA;set up like you should, there is no reason to log in directly as root either.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ordering an OpenBSD VPS and initial thoughts</title>
      <link>/posts/2025/20250424-openbsd-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 19:57:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2025/20250424-openbsd-order/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I thought I would start by sharing my experience of ordering and setting up an&#xA;OpenBSD VPS on OpenBSD.Amsterdam. Before I begin, I have no affiliation with&#xA;them so I gain nothing should you decide to order from them, and I am paying for&#xA;this server out of my own pocket.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ordering&#34;&gt;Ordering&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking around on their page, they have quite a lot of information about their&#xA;setup, so it should be easy to see what the options are and what you are getting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>/posts/2025/20250422-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 17:27:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2025/20250422-welcome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the title so succinctly put it, welcome to my blog! I did not think I&#xA;would ever write one, but here we are.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I aim to write about my experiences running an OpenBSD server and anything&#xA;related to that, as well as other software-related topics that catch my&#xA;interest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve long had an interest in OpenBSD due to their security focus, but did not&#xA;have anything to run it on. Searching for VPS providers, I only found providers&#xA;supporting some Linux distributions or maybe Windows. Digital Ocean was the most&#xA;promising one I found as they supported FreeBSD and I thought it would be&#xA;possible to get OpenBSD running there as well. They unfortunately ended support&#xA;for FreeBSD back in 2022 so I considered that a dead end. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen various&#xA;&amp;ldquo;hacks&amp;rdquo; to get OpenBSD running by installing Linux first, then booting into&#xA;the recovery image, download the installer and re-format the disk, but I did&#xA;not want to try that. I was looking for someone officially supporting OpenBSD by having&#xA;images for it already, or at least having the option to upload a custom image for&#xA;installation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About this blog</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this before I&amp;rsquo;ve even begun, so what this blog will eventually be&#xA;about is actually unknown at this point in time. I have a plan, though.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am generally interested in software and how to develop/build/run it, and I find&#xA;the learning process rewarding. To reinforce and help me remember what I learn I&#xA;find it helpful to write it down as I go along. Doing that in public as I&amp;rsquo;m doing&#xA;here is a little bit scary, but hopefully it will push me to do a little bit&#xA;better than just notes in a notebook just for myself. I hope this will also help&#xA;me let me know if I know the topic as well as I think I do or not. If I can&amp;rsquo;t&#xA;explain it well enough to to others so I think they would understand it, I&#xA;probably don&amp;rsquo;t. I find it is also helpful having my own words to look back on if&#xA;and when I want to revisit a subject.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mastodon</title>
      <link>/mastodon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/mastodon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to reach me, I can be found on Mastodon as &lt;a href=&#34;https://mastodon.bsd.cafe/@noexec&#34;&gt;@noexec@bsd.cafe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
